Guide to the Cornell University Library, Uris Library records, 1891-1996
Uris Library Records, 1891-1996
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Library, Uris Library records, 1891-1996
13-16-3309
Cornell University. Library. Uris Library
1.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, pamphlets, handbooks, architectural drawings
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection includes speeches, correspondence, pamphlets, handbooks, materials from displays/exhibitions, architectural drawings of renovation projects, and comment and suggestion sheets, some with replies.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Uris Library, designed by William Henry Miller and located on the Arts Quad, was the first separate library building on campus. It is now the main undergraduate library.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection includes speeches, correspondence, pamphlets, handbooks, materials from displays/exhibitions, architectural drawings of renovation projects, and comment and suggestion sheets, some with replies.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Cornell University. Libraries.
Form and Genre Terms:
Drawings, architectural.; Manuals.; Pamphlets.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Speeches, 1959-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Uris undergraduate library, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1961-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- New addition, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Newspaper clippings, 1898-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Pamphlets/handbooks, 1962-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Uris Library (The University Library), 1891-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Display (various materials, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Uris Library I, II, III [display], 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
- Architect's drawings, 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photos, 195--1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Myer's Bindery, 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Memoranda on need for undergraduate library, 1949-1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Kirby Room, 1965-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Case 9: The Paper Chase, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Case 8: Passages, [1996] (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous exhibit items, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 20)
- The Best of C & S, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Suggestions notebook, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Comments and replies, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
- Uris Library history display, 19-- (Box 2)